<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>AN<lb />ANTIQUARY</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>s one that has his Being
  in this Age, but<lb />his Life and Converſation is in the Days
  of<lb />old. He deſpiſes the preſent Age as an Inno-<lb />vation, and
  ſlights the future ; but has a great<lb />Value for that, which is
  paſt and gone, like<lb />the Madman, that fell in Love with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Cleopatra</hi>.<lb />He is an old
  frippery-Philoſopher, that has<lb />ſo ſtrange a natural Affection to
  worm-eaten<lb />Speculation, that it is apparent he has a Worm<lb />in
  his Skull. He honours his Forefathers and<lb />Fore-mothers, but
  condemns his Parents as<lb />too modern, and no better than Upſtarts.
  He<lb />neglects himſelf, becauſe he was born in his<lb />own Time,
  and ſo far off Antiquity, which<lb />he ſo much admires ; and repines,
  like a<lb />younger Brother, becauſe he came ſo late into<lb />the
  World. He ſpends the one half of his<lb />Time in collecting old
  inſignificant Trifles,<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>and the other in ſhewing them, which he takes<lb />ſingular Delight
  in ; becauſe the oftener he does<lb />it, the further they are from
  being new to him.<lb />All his Curiouſities take place of one
  another<lb />according to their Seniority, and he values<lb />them not
  by their Abilities, but their Standing.<lb />He has a great Veneration
  for Words that are<lb />ſtricken in Years, and are grown ſo aged,
  that<lb />they have out-lived their Employments---Theſe<lb />he uſes
  with a Reſpect agreeable to their An-<lb />tiquity, and the good
  Services they have done.<lb />He throws away his Time in enquiring
  after<lb />that which is paſt and gone ſo many Ages ſince,<lb />like
  one that ſhoots away an Arrow, to find<lb />out another that was loſt
  before. He fetches<lb />things out of Duſt and Ruins, like the
  Fable<lb />of the chymical Plant raiſed out of its own<lb />Aſhes. He
  values one old Invention, that is<lb />loſt and never to be recovered,
  before all the<lb />new ones in the World, tho’ never ſo
  uſeful.<lb />The whole Buſineſs of his Life is the ſame with<lb />his,
  that ſhows the Tombs at
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Westminster</hi>, only<lb />the one does
  it for his Pleaſure, and the other<lb />for Money. As every Man has
  but one Fa-<lb />ther, but two Grand-Fathers and a World<lb />of
  Anceſtors ; ſo he has a proportional Value<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>for Things that are antient, and the further off<lb />the
  greater.</p>
  <p>He is a great Time-ſerver, but it is of Time<lb />out of Mind, to
  which he conforms exactly,<lb />but is wholly retied from the preſent.
  His<lb />Days were ſpent and gone long before he came<lb />into the
  World, and ſince his only Buſineſs is<lb />to collect what he can out
  of the Ruins of<lb />them. He has ſo ſtrong a natural Affection
  to<lb />any Thing that is old, that he may truly
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">ſay
  to</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Duſt and Worms you are my
  Father, and to Rot-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">tenneſs
  thou are my Mother</hi>. He has no Provi-<lb />dence nor Fore-ſight ;
  for all his Contempla-<lb />tions look backward upon the Days of
  old,<lb />and his Brains are turned with them, as if he<lb />walked
  backwards. He had rather interpret<lb />one obſcure Word in any old
  ſenſeleſs Diſ-<lb />courſe, than be the Author of the moſt
  ingenious<lb />new one ; and with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Scaliger</hi> would ſell the<lb />Empire
  of <hi rendition="simple:italic">Germany</hi><note>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">And with</hi> Scaliger
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">would ſell the Empire of Germany</hi>]
    This al-<lb />ludes to a ranting Exclamation of
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Scaliger</hi>’s upon an Ode in
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Horace</hi>,<lb />which he was
    particularly pleased with.</p>
  </note> (if it were in his Power)<lb />for an old Song. He devours an
  old Manuſ-<lb />cript with greater Reliſh than Worms and
  Moths<lb />do, and, though there be nothing in it, values<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>it above any Thing printed, which he accounts<lb />but a Novelty.
  When he happens to cure a<lb />ſmall Botch in an old Author, he is as
  proud<lb />of it, as if he had got the Philoſophers Stone,<lb />and
  could cure all the Diſeaſes of Mankind.<lb />He values things
  wrongfully upon their Anti-<lb />quity, forgetting that the moſt
  modern are<lb />really the moſt ancient of all Things in
  the<lb />World, like thoſe that reckon their Pounds<lb />before their
  Shillings and Pence, of which they<lb />are made up. He eſteems no
  Cuſtoms but ſuch<lb />as have outlived themſelves, and are long
  ſince<lb />out of Uſe ; as the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Catholics</hi> allow of no
  Saints,<lb />but ſuch as are dead, and the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fanatics</hi>, Op-<lb />poſition, of
  none but the Living.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
