<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />PROUD MAN</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>S a Fool in Fermentation,
  that ſwells and<lb />boils over like a Porridge-Pot. He ſets
  out<lb />his Feathers like an Owl, to ſwell and ſeem<lb />bigger than
  he is. He is troubled with a Tu-<lb />mour and Inflammation of
  Self-Conceit, that<lb />renders every Part of him ſtiff and
  uneaſy.<lb />He has given himſelf Sympathetic Love-Pow-<lb />der, that
  works upon him to Dotage, and has<lb />transformed him into his own
  Miſtreſs. He<lb />is his own Gallant, and makes moſt
  paſſionate<lb />Addreſſes to his own dear Perfections. He<lb />commits
  Idolatry to himſelf, and worſhips<lb />his own Image ; though there is
  no Soul living<lb />of his Church but himſelf, yet he believes
  as<lb />the Church believes, and maintains his Faith<lb />with the
  Obſtinacy of a <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fanatic.</hi> He is his
  own<lb />Favourite, and advance himſelf not only above<lb />his Merit,
  but all Mankind ; is both
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Damon</hi><lb />and
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Pythias</hi> to his own dear ſelf, and
  values his<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Crony above his Soul. He gives Place to no<lb />Man but himſelf,
  and that with very great<lb />Diſtance to all others, whom he eſteems
  not<lb />worthy to approach him. He believes what-<lb />ſoever he has
  receives a Value in being his ;<lb />as a Horſe in a Nobleman’s Stable
  will bear a<lb />greater Price than in a common Market. He<lb />is ſo
  proud, that he is as hard to be acquainted<lb />with himſelf as with
  others ; for he is very<lb />apt to forget who he is, and knows
  himſelf<lb />only ſuperficially ; therefore he treats
  himſelf<lb />civilly as a ſtranger with Ceremony and
  Com-<lb />pliment, but admits of no Privacy. He ſtrives<lb />to look
  bigger than himſelf, as well as others,<lb />and is no better than his
  own Paraſite and<lb />Flatterer. A little Flood will make a
  ſhallow<lb />Torrent ſwell above its Banks, and rage, and<lb />foam,
  and yield a roaring Noiſe, while a deep<lb />ſilent Stream glides
  quietly on. So a vain-<lb />glorious inſolent proud Man ſwells with a
  little<lb />frail Proſperity, grows big and loud, and over-<lb />flows
  his Bounds, and when he ſinks, leaves<lb />Mud and Dirt behind him.
  His Carriage is<lb />as glorious and haughty, as if he were
  advan-<lb />ced upon Men’s Shoulders, or tumbled over<lb />their Heads
  like Knipperdolling. He fancies </p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>himſelf a Coloſſe, and ſo he is, for his Head<lb />holds no
  Proportion to his Body, and his foun-<lb />dation is leſſer than his
  upper Stories. We<lb />can naturally take no view of our ſelves,
  un-<lb />leſs we look downwards, to teach us how<lb />humble Admirers
  we ought to be of our own<lb />Values. The ſlighter and leſs ſolid his
  Mate-<lb />rials are, the more Room they take up, and<lb />make him
  ſwell the bigger ; as Feathers and<lb />Cotton will ſtuff Cuſhions
  better than Things<lb />of more cloſe and ſolid Parts.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
