<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>THE<lb />HENPECT MAN</head>
  <p>R<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi><hi rendition="simple:smallcaps">ide</hi>
  behind his Wife, and lets her<lb />wear the Spurs and governs the
  Reins. He<lb />is a Kind of prepoſterous Animal, that
  being<lb />curbed in goes with his Tail forwards. He is<lb />but
  ſubordinate and miniſterial to his Wife,<lb />who commands in chief,
  and he dares do no-<lb />thing without her Order. She takes Place of
  him,<lb />and he creeps in at the Bed's Feet, as if he
  had<lb />married the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Grand
  Seignor's</hi> Daughter, and is<lb />under Correction of her Pantofle.
  He is his<lb />Wife's Villain, and has nothing of his own<lb />further
  than ſhe pleaſes to allow him. When<lb />he was married he promiſed to
  worſhip his<lb />Wife with his Soul inſtead of his Body,
  and<lb />endowed her among his worldly Goods with his<lb />Humanity.
  He changed Sexes with his Wife,<lb />and put off the old Man to put on
  the new<lb />Woman. She ſits as the Helm, and he does<lb />but tug
  like a Slave at the Oar. The little<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Wit he has being held <hi rendition="simple:italic">in capite</hi>
  has rendered all<lb />the reſt of his Concerments liable to
  Pupi-<lb />lage and Wardſhip, and his Wife has the<lb />Tuition of his
  during his or her Life; and<lb />he has no Power to do any Thing of
  himſelf,<lb />but by his Guardian. His Wife manages him<lb />and his
  Eſtate with equal Authority, and he<lb />lives under her aribtrary
  Government and Com-<lb />mand as his ſuperior Office. He is but a
  kind<lb />of Meſſuage and Tenement in the Occupation<lb />of his Wife.
  He and ſhe make up a Kind of<lb />Hermaphrodite, a Monſter, or which
  the one<lb />half is more than the whole; for he is the<lb />weaker
  Veſſel, and but his Wife's Helper. His<lb />Wife eſpouſed and took him
  to Huſband for<lb />better or worſe, and the laſt Word ſtands.<lb />He
  was meant to be his Wife's Head, but being<lb />ſet on at the wrong
  End ſhe makes him ſerve<lb />(like the Jeſuits Devil) for her Feet. He
  is her<lb />Province, an Acquiſition that ſhe took in,<lb />and gives
  Laws to at Indiſcretion; for being<lb />overmatched and too feeble for
  the Encounter,<lb />he was forced to ſubmit and take Quarter.<lb />He
  has inverted the Curſe, and turned it upon<lb />himſelf; for his
  Deſire is towards his Wife,<lb />and ſhe reign over him and with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Eſau</hi> has<lb />ſold his Birthright
  for a Meſs of Matrimony.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>His Wife took his Liberty among his worldly<lb />Goods, to have and
  to hold till Death them<lb />do part. He is but Groom of his
  Wife's<lb />Chamber, and her menial Huſband, that is<lb />always in
  waiting, and a Slave only in the Right<lb />of his Wife.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
