<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]/ / #AN/ #AMORIST/ /
I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>s an Artificer, or Maker of
Love, a ſworn/ Servant to all Ladies, like an Officer in a/ Corporation.
Though no one in particular/ will own any Title to him, yet he never
fails,/ upon all Occaſions, to offer his Services, and/ they as ſeldom
to turnn it back again untouched./ He commits nothing with them, but
himſelf to/ their good Graces ; and they recommend him/ back again to
his own, where he finds ſo kind/ a Reception, that he wonders how he
does/ fail of it every where elſe. His Paſſion is as/ eaſily ſet on Fire
as a Fart, and as ſoon out/ again. He is charged an primed with Love-/
Powder like a Gun, and the leaſt Sparkle of an/ Eye gives Fire to him,
and off he goes, but/ ſeldom, or never, hits the Mark. He has com-/ mon
Places and Precedents of Repartees and/ Letters for all Occaſions ; and
falls as readily/ into his Method of making love, as a Parſon/</p>
<milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
<p>does into his Form of Matrimony. He con- verſes, as Angela are ſaid
to do, by Intuition, and expreſſes himſelf by Sighs moſt ſignificant-
ly. He follows his Viſits, as Men do their Buſineſs, and is very
induſtrious in waiting on the Ladies, where his Affairs lie ; among
which thoſe of greateſt Concernment are
<hi rendition="simple:italic">Queſtions and Commands, Purpoſes,</hi> and
other ſuch received Forms of With and Converſation ; in which he is ſo
deeply ſtudied, that in all Queſtions and Doubts that ariſe, he is
appealed to, and very learnedly declares, which was the moſt true and
primitive Way of proceeding in the pureſt Times. For theſe Virtues he
never fails of his Summons to all Balls, where he manages the
Country-Dances with ſingular Judgment, and is frequently an Aſſiſtant at
L'hombre; and theſe are all the Uſes they make of his Parts, beſide the
Sport they give themſelves in laughing at him, which he takes for
ſingular Favours, and interprets to his own Advantage, though it never
goes further; for all his Employments being public, he is never admitted
to any pri- vate Services, and they deſpiſe him as not Wo- man's Meat:
For he applies to too many to be truſted by any one; as Baſtards by
having many Fathers, have none at all. He goes often</p>
<milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
<p>mounted in a Coach as a Convoy, to guard the/ Ladies, to take the
Duſt in <hi rendition="simple:italic">Hyde-Park</hi>; where/ by his
prudent Management of the Glaſs Win-/ dows he ſecures them from Beggars,
and re-/ turns fraught with China-Oranges and Ballads./ Thus he is but a
Gentleman-Uſher General,/ and his Buſineſs is to carry one Lady's
Services/ to another, and bring back the others in Ex-/ change./</p>
<milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
