<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>AN<lb />Astrologer</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi><hi rendition="simple:smallcaps">s</hi>
  one that expounds upon the Planets, and<lb />teaches to conſtrue the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Accidents</hi> by the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">due<lb />joining of Stars in
  Conſtruction.</hi> He talks with<lb />them by dumb Signs, and can tell
  what they<lb />mean by their twinckling, and ſquinting upon<lb />one
  another, as well as they themſelves. He<lb />is a Spy upon the Stars,
  and can tell what they<lb />are doing, by the Company they keep, and
  the<lb />Houſes they frequent. They have no Power to<lb />do any Thing
  alone, until ſo many meet, as<lb />will make a
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Quorum.</hi>He is Clerk of the
  Com-<lb />mittee to them, and draws up all their Orders,<lb />that
  concern either public or private Affairs.<lb />He keeps all their
  Accompts for them, and<lb />ſums them up, not by
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Debtor,</hi> but by
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Creditor</hi><lb />alone, a more
  compendious Way. They do<lb />ill to make them have ſo much Authority
  over<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>the Earth, which, perhaps, has as much as<lb />any one of them but
  the Sun, and as much<lb />Right to ſit and vote in their Councils, as
  any<lb />other : But becauſe there are but ſeven Electors<lb />of the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">German</hi> Empire, they will allow of
  no<lb />more to diſpoſe of all other ; and moſt fooliſhly<lb />and
  unnaturally depoſe their own Parent of its<lb />Inheritance; rather
  than acknowledge a Defect<lb />in their own Rules. Theſe Rules are all
  they<lb />have to ſhew for their Title ; and yet not one<lb />of them
  can tell whether thoſe they had them<lb />from came honeſtly by them.
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Virgil's</hi> Deſ-<lb />cription of
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fame,</hi> that reaches from
  Earth<lb />to the Stars, <hi rendition="simple:italic">tam ficti
  pravique tenax,</hi> to carry<lb />Lies and Knavery, will ſerve
  Aſtrologers with-<lb />out any ſenſible Variation. He is a
  Fortune-<lb />Seller, a Retailer of Deſtiny, and petty Chap-<lb />man
  to the Planets. He caſts Nativities as<lb />Gameſters do falſe Dice,
  and by ſlurring and<lb />palming
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">ſextile, quartile,</hi> and
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">trine,</hi> like
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">ſize,</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">quater,
  trois,</hi> can throw what chance he<lb />pleaſes. He ſets a Figure,
  as Cheats do a Main<lb />at Hazard ; and Gulls throw away their
  Money<lb />at it. He festches the Grounds of his Art ſo<lb />far off,
  as well from Reaſon, as the Stars, that,<lb />like a Traveller, he is
  allowed to lye by Au-<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>thority. And as Beggars, that have no Money<lb />themſelves,
  believe all others have, and beg<lb />of thoſe, that have as little as
  themſelves : So<lb />the ignorant Rabble believe in him,
  though<lb />he has no more Reaſon for what he profeſſes,<lb />than
  they.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
