<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />VINTNER</head>
  <p>H<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>ANGS out his Buſh to ſhew
  he has not<lb />good Wine ; for that, the Proverb ſays, needs it not.
  If wine were as neceſſary as<lb />Bread, he would ſtand in the Pillory
  for ſelling<lb />falſe Meaſure, as well as Bakers do for
  falſe<lb />Weight ; but ſince it is at every Man’s Choice<lb />to come
  to his Houſe or not, thoſe that do, are<lb />guilty of half the
  Injuries he does them, and<lb />he believes the reſt to be none at
  all, becauſe<lb />no Injury can be done to him, that is
  willing<lb />to take it. He had rather ſell bad Wine, than<lb />good
  that ſtands him in no more, for it makes<lb />Men ſooner drunk, and
  then they are the eaſier<lb />over-reckoned. By the Knaveries he
  acts<lb />above-board, which every Man ſees, one may<lb />eaſily take
  a Meaſure of thoſe he does under<lb />Ground in his Cellar ; for he
  that will pick<lb />a Man’s Pocket to his Face, will not ſtick
  to<lb />uſe him worſe in private when he knows no-<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>thing of it. When he has poiſoned his<lb />Wines he raiſes his
  Price, and to make amends<lb />for that abates his Meaſure, for he
  thinks it<lb />a greater Sin to commit Murder for ſmall<lb />Gains,
  than a valuable Conſideration. He<lb />does not only ſpoil and deſtroy
  his Wines, but<lb />an ancient reverend Proverb, with brewing
  and<lb />racking, that ſays, <hi rendition="simple:italic">In vino
  veritas</hi>, for there<lb />is no Truth in his, but all falſe and
  ſophiſtica-<lb />ted ; for he can counterfeit Wine as
  cunningly<lb />as <hi rendition="simple:italic">Apelles</hi> did
  Grapes, and cheat Men with it,<lb />as
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">he</hi> did Birds. He brings every
  Bottle of<lb />Wine he draws to the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Bar</hi>, to confeſs it to be<lb />a
  Cheat, and afterwards puts himſelf upon<lb />the Mercy of the Company.
  He is an
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Anti-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">chriſtian</hi>
  Cheat ; for Chriſt turned Water into<lb />Wine, and he turns Wine into
  Water. He<lb />ſcores all his Reckonings upon two Tables<lb />made
  like thoſe of the ten Commandments, that<lb />he may be put in Mind to
  break them as oft as<lb />poſſibly he can ; eſpecially that of
  ſtealing and<lb />bearing falſe Witneſs againſt his
  Neighbour,<lb />when he draws him bad Wine and ſwears it is<lb />good,
  and that he can take more for the Pipe<lb />than the Wine will yield
  him by the Bottle,<lb />a Trick that a
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Jesuit</hi> taught him to cheat
  his<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>own Conſcience with. When he is found to<lb />over-reckon
  notoriouſly, he has one common<lb />Evaſion for all, and that is to
  ſay it was a<lb />Miſtake, by which he means, that he
  thought<lb />they had not been ſober enough to diſcover it ;<lb />for
  if it had paſt, there had been no Error at<lb />all in the
  Caſe.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
