<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />LOVER</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>S a Kind of
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Goth</hi> and
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Vandal</hi>, that leaves<lb />his native
  Self to ſettle in another, or a<lb />Planter that forſakes his
  Country, where he<lb />was born, to labour and dig in
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Virginia</hi>.<lb />His Heart is catched
  in a Net with a Pair of<lb />bringht ſhining Eyes, as Larks are with
  Pieces<lb />of a looking-Glaſs. He makes heavy Com_<lb />plaints
  againſt it for deſerting of him, and<lb />deſires to have another in
  Exchange for it,<lb />which is a very unreaſonable Requeſt ; for
  if<lb />it betrayed its boſom Friend, what will it do<lb />to a
  Stranger, that ſhould give it Truſt and<lb />Entertainment ? He binds
  himſelf, and cries<lb />out he is robbed of his Heart, and charges
  the<lb />Innocent with it, only to get a good Com-<lb />poſition, or
  another for it, againſt Con-<lb />ſcience and Honeſty. He talks much
  of his<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Flame, and pretends to be burnt by his Miſ-<lb />treſs’s Eyes, for
  which he requires Satisfaction<lb />from her, like one that ſets his
  Houſe on Fire<lb />to get a Brief for charitable
  Contributions.<lb />He makes his Miſtreſs all of Stars, and
  when<lb />ſhe is unkind, rails at them, as if they did
  ill<lb />Offices between them, and being of her Kin<lb />ſet her
  againſt him. He falls in Love as Men<lb />fall ſick when their Bodies
  are inclined to it,<lb />and imputes that to his Miſtreſſes
  Charms,<lb />which is really in his own Temper ; for when<lb />that is
  altered, the other vaniſhes of it ſelf, and<lb />therefore one ſaid
  not amiſs,</p>
  <p>------The Lilly and the Roſe<lb />Not in her Cheeks, but in thy
  Temper grows.</p>
  <p>When his Deſires are grown up, they ſwarm,<lb />and fly out to ſeek
  a new Habitation, and<lb />whereſoever they light they fix like Bees,
  among<lb />which ſome late Philoſophers have obſerved<lb />that it is
  a Female that leads all the reſt. Love<lb />is but a Clap of the Mind,
  a Kind of run-<lb />ning of the Fancy, that breaks out, if it
  be<lb />not ſtopped in Time, into Botches of heroic<lb />Rime ; for
  all Loverrs are poets for the Time<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>being, and make their Ladies a Kind of mo-<lb />ſaic Work of
  ſeveral coloured Stones joined<lb />together by a ſtrong Fancy, but
  very ſtiff and<lb />unnatural ; and though they ſteal Stars
  from<lb />Heaven, as <hi rendition="simple:italic">Prometheus</hi> did
  Fire, to animate<lb />them, all will not make them alive,
  nor<lb />alives-liking.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
