<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>THE<lb />HENPECT MAN</head>
  <p>R<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>IDES behind his Wife, and
  lets her<lb />wear the Spurs and governs the Reins. He<lb />is a Kind
  of prepoſterous Animal, that being<lb />curbed in goes with his Tail
  forwards. He is<lb />but ſubordinate and miniſterial to his
  Wife,<lb />who commands in chief, and he dares do no-<lb />thing
  without her Order. She takes Place of him,<lb />and he creeps in at
  the Bed’s Feet, as if he had<lb />married the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Grand Seignor</hi>’s Daughter, and
  is<lb />under Correction of her Pantofle. He is his<lb />Wife’s
  Villain, and has nothing of his own<lb />further than ſhe pleaſes to
  allow him. When<lb />he was married he promiſed to worſhip
  his<lb />Wife with his Soul inſtead of his Body, and<lb />endowed her
  among his worldly Goods with his<lb />Humanity. He changed Sexes with
  his Wife,<lb />and put off the old Man to put on the new<lb />Woman.
  She ſits as the Helm, and he does<lb />but tug like a Slave at the
  Oar. The little<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt; HEAD</p>
  <p>Wit he has being held <hi rendition="simple:italic">in capite</hi>
  has rendered all/ the reſt of his Concerments liable to Pupi-/ lage
  and Wardſhip, and his Wife has the/ Tuition of his during his or her
  Life; and/ he has no Power to do any Thing of himſelf,/ but by his
  Guardian. His Wife manages him/ and his Eſtate with equal Authority,
  and he/ lives under her aribtrary Government and Com-/ mand as his
  ſuperior Officer. He is but a kind/ of Meſſuage and Tenement in the
  Occupation/ of his Wife. He and ſhe make up a Kind of/ Hermaphrodite,
  a Monſter, or which the one/ half is more than the whole; for he is
  the/ weaker Veſſel, and but his Wife's Helper. His/ Wife eſpouſed and
  took him to Huſband for/ better or worſe, and the laſt Word ſtands./
  He was meant to be his Wife's Head, but being/ ſet on at the wrong End
  ſhe makes him ſerve/ (like the Jeſuits Devil) for her Feet. He is her/
  Province, an Acquiſition that ſhe took in,/ and gives Laws to at
  Indiſcretion; for being/ overmatched and too feeble for the
  Encounter,/ he was forced to ſubmit and take Quarter./ He has inverted
  the Curſe, and turned it upon/ himſelf; for his Deſire is towards his
  Wife,/ and ſhe reign over him and with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Eſau</hi> has/ ſold his Birthright for a
  Meſs of Matrimony./ ======= Wit he has being held
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">in capite</hi> has rendered all<lb />the
  reſt of his Concerments liable to Pupi-<lb />lage and Wardſhip, and
  his Wife has the<lb />Tuition of his during his or her Life ;
  and<lb />he has no Power to do any Thing of himſelf,<lb />but by his
  Guardian. His Wife manages him<lb />and his Eſtate with equal
  Authority, and he<lb />lives unde rher aribtrary Government and
  Com-<lb />mand as his ſuperior Office. He is but a kind<lb />of
  Meſſuage and Tenement in the Occupation<lb />of his Wife. He and ſhe
  make up a Kind of<lb />Hermaphrodite, a Monſter, or which the
  one<lb />half is more than the whole ; for he is the<lb />weaker
  Veſſel, and but his Wife's Helper. His<lb />Wife eſpouſed and took him
  to Huſband for<lb />better or worſe, and the laſt Word ſtands.<lb />He
  was meant to be his Wife's Head, but being<lb />ſet on at the wrong
  End ſhe makes him ſerve<lb />(like the Jeſuits Devil) for her Feet. He
  is her<lb />Province, an Acquiſition that ſhe took in,<lb />and gives
  Laws to at Indiſcretion ; for being<lb />overmatched and too feeble
  for the Encounter,<lb />he was forced to ſubmit and take
  Quarter.<lb />He has inverted the Curſe, and turned it
  upon<lb />himſelf ; for his Deſire is towards his Wife,<lb />and ſhe
  reign over him, and with <hi rendition="simple:italic">Eſau</hi>
  has<lb />ſold his Birthright for a Meſs of
  Matrimony.<lb />&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;
  159ee409900c95c1506e687c9b8acc6310246559</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>His Wife took his Liberty among his worldly<lb />Goods, to have and
  to hold till Death them<lb />do part. He is but Groom of his
  Wife’s<lb />Chamber, and her menial Huſband, that is<lb />always in
  waiting, and a Slave only in the Right<lb />of his Wife.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
