<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />SMALL POET</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>S one, that would fain
  make himſelf that,<lb />which
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Nature</hi> never meant him ; like a
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fa-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">natic</hi>,
  that inſpires himſelf with his own<lb />Whimſies. He ſets up
  Haberdaſher of ſmall<lb />Poetry, with a very ſmall Stock, and no
  Credit.<lb />He believes it is Invention enough to find out<lb />other
  Men’s Wit ; and whatſoever he lights upon<lb />either in Books, or
  Company, he makes bold<lb />with as his own. This he puts together ſo
  un-<lb />towardly, that you may perceive his own Wit<lb />has the
  Rickets, by the ſwelling Diſproportion<lb />of the Joints. Imitation
  is the whole Sum of<lb />him ; and his Vein is but an Itch or Clap,
  that<lb />he has catched of others ; and his Flame like<lb />that of
  Charcoals, that were burnt before :<lb />But as he wants Judgment to
  underſtand what<lb />is beſt, he naturally takes the worſt, as
  being<lb />moſt agreeable to his own Talent. You may<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>know his Wit not to be natural, ’tis ſo un-<lb />quiet and
  troubleſome in him : For as thoſe,<lb />that have Money but ſeldom,
  are always ſhak-<lb />ing their Pockets, when they have it ; ſo
  does<lb />he, when he thinks he has got ſomething, that<lb />will make
  him appear. He is a perpetual Tal-<lb />ker ; and you may know by the
  Freedom of his<lb />Diſcourſe, that he came light by it, as
  Thieves<lb />ſpend freely what they get. He meaſures other<lb />Men’s
  Wits by <hi rendition="simple:italic">their</hi> Modeſty, and his own
  by<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">his</hi> Confidence. He makes
  nothing of writing<lb />Plays, becauſe he has not Wit enough to
  un-<lb />derstand the Difficulty. This makes him ven-<lb />ture to
  talk and ſcribble, as Chowſes do to play<lb />with cunning Gameſters,
  until they are cheated<lb />and laughed at. He is always talking of
  Wit,<lb />as thoſe, that have bad Voices, are always ſing-<lb />ing
  out of Tune ; and thoſe, that cannot play,<lb />delight to fumble on
  Inſtruments. He grows<lb />the unwiſer by other Men’s Harms ; for
  the<lb />worſe others write, he finds the more Encou-<lb />ragement to
  do ſo too. His Greedineſs of<lb />Praiſe is ſo eager, that he ſwallows
  any Thing,<lb />that comes in the Likeneſs of it, how
  notorious<lb />and palpable ſoever, and is as Shot-free
  againſt<lb />any Thing, that may leſſen his good Opinion<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>of himſelf---This renders him incurable, like<lb />Diſeaſes, that
  grow inſenſible.</p>
  <p>If you diſlike him it is at your own Peril ;<lb />he is ſure to put
  in a Caveat beforehand againſt<lb />your Understanding ; and, like a
  Malefactor<lb />in Wit, is always furniſhed with
  Exceptions<lb />againſt his Judges. This puts him upon
  perpe-<lb />tual Apologies, Excuſes, and Defences, but<lb />ſtill by
  Way of Defiance, in a Kind of whif-<lb />fling Strain, without Regard
  of any Man,<lb />that ſtands in the Way of his Pageant.<lb />Where he
  thinks he may do it ſafely, he<lb />will confidently own other Men’s
  Writings ;<lb />and where he fears the Truth may be
  diſcovered,<lb />he will by feeble Denials and feigned
  Inſinua-<lb />tions give Men Occaſion to ſuppoſe ſo.</p>
  <p>If he underſtands <hi rendition="simple:italic">Latin</hi> or
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Greek</hi> he ranks<lb />himſelf among
  the Learned, deſpiſes the Igno-<lb />rant, talks Criticiſms out of
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Scaliger</hi>, and re-<lb />peats
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Martial</hi>'s baudy Epigrams, and ſets
  up<lb />his Reſt wholly upon Pedantry. But if he be<lb />not ſo well
  qualified, he crys down all Learning<lb />as pedantic, diſclaims
  Study, and profeſſes to<lb />write with as great Facility, as if his
  Muſe was<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>ſliding down <hi rendition="simple:italic">Parnaſſus</hi>.
  Whatſoever he hears<lb />well ſaid<note>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">Whatſoever he hears well ſaid</hi>,
    &amp;tc. ] In this <hi rendition="simple:italic">Butler</hi> alludes
    to<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Martial</hi>'s Epigram to
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fidentinus</hi>.
    [<hi rendition="simple:italic">footnote cont. next
    page</hi>][^2]</p>
  </note> he ſeizes upon by poetical Licence ;<lb />and one Way makes it
  his own, that is by ill<lb />repeating of it---This he believes to be
  no<lb />more Theft, than it is to take that, which others<lb />throw
  away. By this means his Writings are,<lb />like a Taylor’s Cuſhion, of
  moſaic Work,<lb />made up of ſeveral Scraps ſewed together.<lb />He
  calls a ſlovenly naſty Deſcription <hi rendition="simple:italic">great
  Na-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">ture</hi>, and dull
  Flatneſs <hi rendition="simple:italic">strange Eaſineſs</hi>.
  He<lb />writes down all that comes in his Head, and<lb />makes no
  Choice, becauſe he has nothing to<lb />do it with, that is Judgment.
  He is always<lb />repealing the old Laws of Comedy, and like<lb />the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">long Parliament</hi> making
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Ordinances</hi> in their<lb />Stead ;
  although they are perpetually
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">thrown</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">out</hi>
  of Coffee-Houſes, and come to Nothing.<lb />He is like an
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Italian</hi> Thief, that never
  robs,<lb />but he murthers, to prevent Diſcovery ; ſo ſure<lb />is he
  to cry down the Man from whom he pur-<lb />loins, that his petty
  Larceny of Wit may paſs<lb />unſuſpected. He is but a Copier at beſt,
  and<lb />will never arrive to practice by the Life : For<lb />bar him
  the Imitation of ſomething he has<lb />read, and he has no Image in
  his Thoughts.</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Obſervation and Fancy, the Matter and Form<lb />of juſt Wit, are
  above his Philoſophy. He<lb />appears ſo over concerned in all Men’s
  Wits,<lb />as if they were but Diſparagements of his<lb />own ; and
  crys down all they do, as if they<lb />were Encroachments upon him. He
  takes<lb />Jeſts from the Owners and breaks them,
  as<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Justices</hi> do falſe Weights,
  and Pots that want<lb />Meaſure. When he meets with any
  Thing,<lb />that is very good, he changes it into ſmall<lb />Money,
  like three Groats for a Shilling, to<lb />ſerve ſeveral Occaſions. He
  diſclaims Study,<lb />pretends to take Things in Motion, and to
  ſhoot<lb />flying, which appears to be very true by his<lb />often
  miſſing of his Mark. His Wit is much<lb />troubled with Obſtructions ;
  and he has Fits as<lb />painful as thoſe of the Spleen. He fancies
  him-<lb />ſelf a dainty ſpruce Shepherd, with a Flock and<lb />a fine
  ſilken Shepherdeſs, that follows his Pipe,<lb />as Rats did the
  Conjurers in <hi rendition="simple:italic">Germany</hi>.</p>
  <p>As for <hi rendition="simple:italic">Epithets</hi>, he always
  avoids thoſe, that<lb />are near akin to the Senſse. Such matches
  are<lb />unlawful, and not fit to be made by a
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Chriſtian</hi><lb />Poet ; and therefore
  all his Care is to chuſe out<lb />[^2]:
  [<hi rendition="simple:italic">footnote cont'd from prev. page</hi>]
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Quem recitas meus eſt, O Fidentine,
  libellus :</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Sed male dum
  recitas, incipit eſſe tuus.    Mart. L. 1. Ep. 39.</hi></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>ſuch, as will ſerve, like a wooden Leg, to piece<lb />out a main’d
  Verſe, that wants a Foot or two ;<lb />and if they will but rhimes now
  and then into<lb />the Bargain, or run upon a Letter, it is a
  Work<lb />of Supererrogation.</p>
  <p>For <hi rendition="simple:italic">Similitudes</hi>, he likes the
  hardeſt and moſt<lb />obſcure beſt : For as Ladies wear black
  Patches,<lb />to make their Complexions ſeem fairer than<lb />they
  are ; ſo when an Illuſtration is more ob-<lb />ſcure than the Senſe
  that went before it, it muſt<lb />of Neceſſity make it appear clearer
  than it<lb />did : For Contraries are beſt ſet off with
  Con-<lb />traries.</p>
  <p>He has found out a Way to ſave the Expence<lb />of much Wit and
  Senſe : For he will make<lb />leſs than ſome have prodigally laid out
  upon<lb />five or ſix Words ſerve forty or fifty Lines.<lb />This is a
  thrifty Invention, and very eaſy ; and,<lb />if it were commonly
  known, would much in-<lb />creaſe the Trade of Wit, and maintain a
  Mul-</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>titude of ſmall Poets in conſtant Employment.<lb />He has found out
  a new Sort of poetical
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Geor-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">gics</hi>,
  a Trick of ſowing Wit like clover-graſs<lb />on barren Subjects, which
  would yield nothing<lb />before. This is very uſeful for the
  Times,<lb />wherein, ſome Men ſay, there is no Room left<lb />for new
  Invention. He will take three Grains<lb />of Wit like the Elixir, and
  projecting it upon<lb />the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Iron-Age</hi> turn it immediately into
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Gold---</hi><lb />All the Buſineſs of
  Mankind has preſently<lb />vaniſhed, the whole World has kept
  Holiday ;<lb />there has been no Men but Heroes and Poets,<lb />no
  Women but Nymphs and Shepherdeſſes ;<lb />Tress have born Fritters,
  and Rivers flowed<lb />Plum-Porrige.</p>
  <p>We read that <hi rendition="simple:italic">Virgil</hi> uſed to
  make<note>
    <p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">footnote for next page</hi>]
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">We read that Virgil uſed to make</hi>,
    &amp;c.] This alludes to a Paſſage<lb />in the Life of
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Virgil</hi> aſcribed to
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Donatus</hi>. “ Cum Georgica
    ſcribe-<lb />“ ret traditur quotidie meditatos mane plurimos verſus
    dictare ſo-<lb />“ litus, ac per totum diem retracando ad
    pauciſſimos redigrere :<lb />“ non abſurde carmen ſe urſæ more
    parere dicens, et lambendo<lb />“ demum effingere.</p>
  </note> fifty or<lb />ſixty Verſes in a Morning, and afterwards
  re-<lb />duce them to ten. This was an unthrifty<lb />Vanity, and
  argues him as well ignorant in the<lb />Huſbandry of his own Poetry,
  as <hi rendition="simple:italic">Seneca</hi> ſays<lb />he was in that
  of a Farm ;<note>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">As</hi> Seneca
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">ſays he was in that of a farm</hi>.]
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Seneca</hi> in his 86th<lb />Epiſtle
    finds ſeveral Faults with
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Virgil</hi>'s Rules and Obſervations
    in<lb />Huſbandry, as they are delivered in his
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Georgics</hi>, and adds of him
    ---<lb />“ Qui non quod veriſſime, ſed quid decentiſſime diceretur,
    ad-<lb />“ ſpexit ; nec Agricolas docere voluit, ſed legentes
    delectare.”</p>
  </note> for in plain <hi rendition="simple:italic">Engliſh</hi></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>it was no better than bringing a Noble to Nine-<lb />pence. And as
  ſuch Courſes brought the<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">prodigal
  Son</hi> to eat with Hogs : So they did him<lb />to feed with
  Horſes,<note>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">So they did him to feed with
    Horſes</hi>] This muſt be explained by<lb />the ſame Writer of
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Virgil</hi>’s Life, who informs us,
    that <hi rendition="simple:italic">Virgil</hi> in<lb />his Youth
    ſtudied Phyſic, in which having made great Proficiency,<lb />he
    repaired to <hi rendition="simple:italic">Rome</hi>, and applying
    himſelf to that Branch of it [<hi rendition="simple:italic">footnote
    cont. next page</hi>][^6]</p>
  </note> which were not much<lb />better Company, and may teach us to
  avoid<lb />doing the like. For certainly it is more noble<lb />to take
  four or five Grains of Senſe, and, like<lb />a Gold-Beater, hammer
  them into ſo many<lb />Leaves as will fill a whole Book ; than to
  write<lb />nothing but Epitomies, which many wiſe Men<lb />believe
  will be the Bane and Calamity of Learning.</p>
  <p>When he writes, he commonly ſteers the<lb />Senſe of his Lines by
  the Rhime that is at the<lb />End of them, as Butchers do Calves by
  the<lb />Tail. For when he has made one Line, which<lb />is eaſy
  enough ; and has found out ſome ſturdy<lb />hard Word, that will but
  rhime, he will ham-<lb />mer the Senſe upon it, like a Piece of hot
  Iron<lb />upon an Anvil, into what Form he pleaſes.</p>
  <p>There is no Art in the World ſo rich in<lb />Terms as Poetry ; a
  whole Dictionary is ſcarce</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>able to contain them : For there is hardly a<lb />Pond, a
  Sheep-walk, or a Gravel-pit in
  all<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Greece</hi>, but the antient
  Name of it is become<lb />a Term of Art in Poetry. By this means
  ſmall<lb />Poets have ſuch a Stock of able hard Words lying<lb />by
  them, as <hi rendition="simple:italic">Dryades</hi>,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Hamadryades</hi>,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Aonides</hi>,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fauni</hi>,<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Nymphae</hi>,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Sylvani</hi>,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">&amp;c</hi>. that ſignify nothing at
  all ;<lb />and ſuch a World of pedantic Terms of the<lb />ſame Kind,
  as may ſerve to furniſh all the new<lb />Inventions and
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">thorough-Reformations</hi>, that
  can<lb />happen between this and
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Plato</hi>’s great Year.</p>
  <p>When he writes he never propoſes any Scope<lb />or Purpoſe to
  himſelf, but gives his Genius all<lb />Freedom : For as he, that rides
  abroad for his<lb />Pleaſure, can hardly be out of his Way ; ſo
  he<lb />that writes for his Pleaſure, can ſeldom be be-<lb />ſide his
  Subject. It is an ungrateful Thing to<lb />a noble Wit to be confined
  to any Thing---<lb />To what Purpoſe did the Antients feign
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Pegaſus</hi><lb />to have Wings, if he
  muſt be confined to the<lb />Road and Stages like a Pack-Horſe, or be
  forced<lb />to be obedient to Hedges and Ditches? There-</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>fore he has no Reſpect to Decorum and Pro-<lb />priety of
  Circumſtance ; for the Regard of<lb />Perſons, Times, and Places is a
  Reſtraint too<lb />ſervile to be impoſed upon poetical
  Licence ;<lb />like him that made
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Plato</hi><note>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">Like him that made Plato</hi>,
    &amp;c.] Who this Blunder is to be fa-<lb />thered upon I cannot
    diſcover ; but that which he imputes to
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Per</hi>-<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">ſius</hi>,
    and another of <hi rendition="simple:italic">Juvenal</hi>’s, a
    Paſſage of his own in a Part of his<lb />Proſe Collections called
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Criticiſms upon Books and
    Autohrs</hi>, will ex-<lb />plain ---
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Persius</hi>, ſays he, commits a very
    great Abſurdity, when<lb />laying the Scene of his fourth Satyr in
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Greece</hi>, and bringing in
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">So</hi>-<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">crates</hi>
    reproving a young Stateſmen, he makes him call the
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Græ</hi>-<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">cians</hi>
    Quirites. [<hi rendition="simple:italic">footnote cont. next
    page</hi>][^8]</p>
  </note> confeſs <hi rendition="simple:italic">Juvenal</hi> to
  be<lb />a Philoſopher, or <hi rendition="simple:italic">Perſius</hi>,
  that calls the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Athe</hi>-<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">nians
  Quirites</hi>.</p>
  <p>For <hi rendition="simple:italic">Metaphors</hi>, he uſes to chuſe
  the hardeſt,<lb />and moſt far-fet that he can light
  upon---Theſe<lb />are the Jewels of Eloquence, and therefore
  the<lb />harder they are, the more precious they muſt<lb />be.</p>
  <p>He’ll take ſcant Piece of coarſe Senſe, and<lb />ſtretch it on the
  Tenterhooks of half a ſcore<lb />Rhimes, until it crack that you may
  ſee through<lb />it, and it rattle like a Drum-Head. When<lb />you ſee
  his Verſes hanged up in Tobacco-Shops,<lb />you may ſay, in defiance
  of the Proverb,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">that</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">the
  weakeſt does not always go to the Wall</hi> ; for ’tis</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>well known the Lines are ſtrong enough, and<lb />in that Senſe may
  juſtly take the Wall of any,<lb />that have been written in our
  Language. He<lb />ſeldom makes a Conſcience of his Rhimes ;
  but<lb />will often take the Liberty to make
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">preach</hi><lb />rhime with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Cheat</hi>,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Vote</hi> with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Rogue</hi>, and
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Com</hi>-<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">mittee-Man</hi>
  with <hi rendition="simple:italic">Hang</hi>.</p>
  <p>He’ll make one Word of as many Joints, as<lb />the Tin-Pudding,
  that a Jugler pulls out of<lb />his Throat, and chops in again---What
  think<lb />you of
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">glud-fum-flam-hasta-minantes ?</hi> Some
  of<lb />the old <hi rendition="simple:italic">Latin</hi> Poets<note>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">Some of the old</hi> Latin
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Poets</hi>, &amp;c.] Thus
    <hi rendition="simple:italic">Horace</hi><lb /></p>
  </note> bragged, that their Verſes<lb />were tougher than Braſs, and
  harder than<lb />Marble ; what would they have done, if they<lb />had
  ſeen theſe ? Verily they would have had<lb />more reaſon to wiſh
  themſelves an hundred<lb />Throats, than they then had, to pronounce
  them.</p>
  <p>There are ſome, that drive a Trade in writ-<lb />ing in praiſe of
  other Writers, (like Rooks,</p>
  <quote>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">Exegi monumentum ære
    perennius</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Regalique ſitu
    Pyramidum altius</hi>      <hi rendition="simple:italic">Hor</hi>.
    L. 3. O. 30</p>
  </quote>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>that bet on Gameſters Hands) not at all to ce- lebrate the learned
  Author's Merits, as they would ſhew, but their own Wits, of which he
  is but the Subjec_t. The Letchery of this Va- nity has ſpawned more
  Writers than the * civil Law: * For thoſe, whoſe Modeſty muſt
  notorious Va- pours imaginable. For if the Privilege of Love be
  allowed--* Dicere quae* puduit, ſcribere juſſit Amor,* why ſhould it
  not be ſo in Self- Love too? For if it be Wiſdom to conceal our
  Imperfec_tions, what is it to diſcover our Vir- tues? It is not like,
  that * Nature * gave Men great Parts upon ſuch Terms, as the * Fairies
  <hi rendition="simple:italic"> uſe to give Money, to pinch and leave
  them if they ſpeak of it. They ſay--</hi>Praiſe is but the Shadow of
  Virtue; * and ſure that Virtue is very foolish, that is afraid of its
  own Shadow.</p>
  <p>When he writes * Anograms, * he uſes to lay the Outſides of his
  Verſes even (like a Brick-</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>layer) by a Line of Rhime and Acroſtic, and fill th eMiddle with
  Rubbiſh--In this he imi- tates * Ben Johnson, * but in nothing
  elſe.</p>
  <p>There was one, that lined a Hat-Caſe with a Paper of *
  Benlowſe'<hi rendition="simple:italic">s Poetry--</hi> Prynne * bought
  it by Chance, and put a new Demi-Caſtor into it. The firſt Time he
  wore it he felt only a ſinging in his Head, which within two Days
  turned to a Vertigo--He was let Blood in the Ear by one of the
  State-Phyſicians, and reco- vered; but before he went abroad he writ a
  Poem of Rocks and Seas, in a Stile ſo proper and natural, that it was
  hard to determine, which was ruggeder.</p>
  <p>There is no Fear of Ac_tivity, nor Gambol of Wit, that ever was
  performed by Man, from him that vaults on * Pegasus, * to him that
  tumbles through the Hoop of an Anagram, but * Benlows * has got the
  Maſtery in it, whether it be high-rope Wit, or low-rope Wit. He</p>
  <p>son means was .......</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>has all Sorts of * Echoes, Rebus's, Chronograms,/ &amp;c.* beſides
  * Carwichets, Clenches, * and *
  Quibbles--<hi rendition="simple:italic">/ As for </hi> Altars * and *
  Pyramids * in Poetry, he has/ out-done all Men that Way; for he has/
  made a * Gridiron, * and a * Frying-Pan * in Verſe,/ that, beſide the
  Likeneſs in Shape, the very/ Tone and Sound of the Words did
  perfec_tly/ repreſent the Noiſe, that is made by thoſe/ Utenſils, ſuch
  as the old Poet called * ſartago lo-/ quendi. * When he was Captain,
  he made all/ the Furniture of his Horſe, from the Bit to/ the Crupper,
  in beaten Poetry, every Verſe/ being fitted to the Proportion of the
  Thing,/ with a moral Alluſion of the Senſe to the/ Thing; as the *
  Bridle of Moderation, the Saddle/ of Content, * and * the Crupper of
  Conſtancy;* ſo that/ the ſame Thing was both Epigram and Emblem,/ even
  as Mule is both Horſe and Aſs.</p>
  <p>Some Critics are of Opinion, that Poets/ ought to apply themselves
  to the Imitation of/ * Nature, * and make a Conſcience of digreſſing/
  from her; but he is none of theſe. The an-/ tient Magicians could
  charm down the Moon,/ and force Rivers back to their Springs by
  the/</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Power of Poetry only; and the Moderns will/ undertake to turn the
  Inſide of the Earh out-/ ward (like a Jugler's Pocket) and ſhake the/
  Chesſ out of it, make * Nature * ſhew Tricks like/ an Ape, and the
  Stars run on Errands; but/ ſtill it is by dint of Poetry. And if Poets
  can/ so ſuch noble Feats, they were unwiſe to deſ-/ cend to mean and
  vulgar: For where the rareſt/ and moſt common Things are of a Price
  (as/ they are all one to Poets) it argues Diſease in/ Judgement not to
  chuſe the most curious. Hence/ ſome infer, that the Account they give
  of things/ deſerves no Regard, becauſe they never receive/ any Thing,
  as they find it, into their Compo-/ ſitions, unleſs it agree both with
  the Meaſure/ of their own Fancis, and the Meaſure of their/ Lines,
  which can very ſeldom happen: And/ therefore when they give a
  Character of any/ Thing or Perſon, it does commonly bear no/ more
  Proportions to the Subject, than the Fiſhes/ and Ships in a Map do to
  the Scale. But let/ ſuch know, that Poets, as well as Kings, ought/
  rather to conſider what is fit for them to give,/ than others to
  receive; that they are fain to/ have regard to the Exchange of
  Language, and/</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>write high or low, according as that runs:/ For in this Age, when
  the ſmallest Poet ſeldom/ goes below more then moſt, it were a Shame
  for/ a grater and more noble Poet not to out-throw/ that cut a
  Bar.</p>
  <p>T<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>here was a * Tobacco-Man,
  * that wrapped / <hi rendition="simple:italic">Spaniſh </hi> Tobacco
  in a Paper of Verſes, which/
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Benlows</hi> had written againſt the *
  Pope, * which/ by a natural Antipathy, that his Wit has to / any Thing
  that's Catholic, ſpoiled the Tobacco;/ for it preſently turned
  Mundungus. This Au-/ thor will take an * English * Word, and, like
  the/ * Frenchman, * that ſwallowed Water and ſpit it/ out Wine, with a
  little Heaving and Straining/ would turn it immediately into * Latin,*
  as * plun-/ derat ille Domos<hi rendition="simple:italic">--Mille
  </hi> Hocopokiana, * and a thou-/ ſand ſuch./ / ##There was a young
  Practitioner in Poetry,/ that found there was no good to be done
  with-/ out a Miſtreſs: For he, that writes of Love/ before he hath
  tried it, doth but travel by the/ Map; and he, that makes Love without
  a/ Dame, does like a Gameſter, that plays for/ / #*More the moſt]
  There is an appearance Defect or Error in theſe/ Words; but I leave it
  to the Reader to ſupply or correct./</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Nothing. He thought it convenient therefore,/ firſt to furniſh
  himſelf with a Name for his/ Miſstress beforehand, that he might not
  be to/ ſeek, when his Merit or good Fortune ſhould/ beſtow her upon
  him: for every Poet is his/ miſtreſſe's Godfather, and gives her a
  new/ Name, like a Nun that takes Orders. He was/ very curious to ſit
  himself with a handſome/ Word of a turnable Sound; but could light/
  upon none, that ſome Poet or other had not / made uſe of before. He
  was therefore forced/ to fall to coining, and was ſeveral Months be-/
  fore he could light on one, that pleaſed him/ perfectly. But after he
  had overcome that Dif-/ ficulty, he found a greater remaining, to get
  a/ Lady to own him. He accoſted ſome of all/ Sorts, and gave them to
  underſtand, both in/ Proſe and Verſe, how incomparably happy it/ was
  in his Power to make his Miſtreſs, but/ could never convert any of
  them. At length/ he was fain to make his Landreſs ſupply that/ Place
  as Proxy, until his good Fortune, or/ ſomebody of better Quality would
  be more / kind to him, which after a while he neither/ hoped nor cared
  for; for how mean Toever her/ Condition was before, when he had once
  pre-/ tended to her, ſhe was ſure to be a Nymph and/</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>a Goddeſs. For what greater Honour can a/ Woman be capable of, than
  to be tranſlated/ into precious Stones and Stars? No Herald in/ the
  World can go higher. Beſides se found no/ Man can uſe that Freedom of
  Hyperbole in the/ Character of a Perſon commonly known (as/ great
  Ladies are) which we can in deſcribing/ one ſo obſcure and unknown,
  that nobody can/ diſprove him. For he, that writes but one/ Sonnet
  upon any of the public Perſons, ſhall/ be ſure to have his Reader at
  ever third Word/ cry out--What an Aſs is this to call * Spaniſh/ paper
  and Ceruſe Lillies and Roſes, * or * claps In-/ fluences--* To ſay, *
  the Graces are her waiting Wo-/ men, * when they are known to be no
  better/ than her Bawdes--that * Day breaks from her/ Eyes,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">when ſhe looks aſquint--Or that </hi>
  her/ Breath perfumes the Arabian Winds, * when ſhe/ puffs Tobacco?/ /
  ##It is no mean Art to improve a Language,/ and find out Words, that
  are not only removed/ from common uſe, but rich in Conſonanats,/ the
  Nerves and Sinews of Speech, to raiſe a/ / ---</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>ſft and feeble Language like ours to the Pitch/ of * High-Dutch,*
  as he did, that writ</p>
  <quote>
    <list type="unordered">
      <item>
        <p>Arts rattling Foreſkins ſhrilling Bagpipes quell.*/</p>
      </item>
    </list>
  </quote>
  <p>This is not the only the moſt elegant, but moſt po-/ litic Way of
  Writing, that a Poet can uſe; for I/ know no Defence like it to
  preſerve a Poem from/ the Torture of thoſe that liſp and ſtammer./ He
  that wants Teeth may as well venture upon/ a Piece of tough horny
  Brawn as ſuch a Line,/ for he will look like an Aſs eating
  Thiſtles.</p>
  <p>He never begins a Work without an Invoca-/ tion of his * Muse; *
  for it is not fit that ſhe ſhould/ appear in public, to ſhew her Skill
  before ſhe/ is entreated, as Gentlewomen do not uſe to / ſing, until
  they are applied to, and often deſired.</p>
  <p>I ſhall not need to ſay any this of the Ex-/ cellence of Poetry,
  ſince it has been already/ performed by many excellent Perſons, among/
  whom ſome have lately undertaken to prove, that/ the civil Government
  cannot poſſibly ſubſiſt with-/ out it, which, for my Part, I believe
  to be true</p>
  <list type="unordered">
    <item>
      <p>ſome have lately. <hi rendition="simple:italic">] This alludes
      to </hi> Davenant--See * G---</p>
    </item>
  </list>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>in a poetical Senſe, and more probable to be/ received of it, than
  thoſe ſtrange Feats of/ building Walls and making Trees dance,/ which
  Antiquity aſcribes to Verſe. And though/ * Philoſophers * are of a
  contrary Opinion, and will/ not allow Poets fit to live in a
  Commonwealth,/ their Partiality is plainer than their Reaſons;/ for
  they have no other Way to pretend to this/ Prerogative themſelves, as
  they do, but by re-/ moving Poets, whom they know to have a/ fairer
  Title; and this they do unjuſtly, that/ * Plato, * who firſt baniſhed
  Poets his Republic,/ forgot that the very Commonwealth was poe-/
  tical. I ſhall ſay nothing to them, but only/ deſire the World to
  conſider, how happily it is/ like to be governed by thoſe, that are as
  ſo per-/ petual a civil War among themſelves, that if we/ ſhould
  ſubmit ourſelves to their own Reſolution/ of this Question, and be
  content to allow them/ only fit to rule if they could but conclude it/
  ſo themselves, they would never agree upon it--/ Mean while there is
  no leſs Certainty and Agree-/ ment in Poetry than the Mathematics; for
  they/ all ſubmit the to the ſame Rules without Diſpute or/
  Controverſy. But whoſoever ſhall pleaſe to look/ into the Records of
  Antiquity ſhall find their/ Title ſo unqueſtioned, that the greatest
  Princess</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>in the whole World have been glad to derive/ their Pedigrees, and
  their Power too, from/ Poets. * Alexander * the great had no wiſer a
  Way/ so ſecure the Empire to himſelf by * Right,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">/ which he had gotten by </hi> Force, *
  then by de-/ claring himſelf the Son of * Jupiter; * and who/ was *
  Jupiter * but the Son of a Poet? So * Caeſar
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">/ and all </hi> Rome * was transported
  with Joy, when a/ Poet made * Jupiter * his Colleague in the Empire;/
  and when * Jupiter * governed, what did the/ Poets, that governed
  Jupiter?</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
