<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />MELANCHOLY MAN</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>s one, that keeps the
  worſt Company in the<lb />World, that is, his own; and tho' he be
  al-<lb />ways falling out and quarrelling with himſelf,<lb />yet he
  has not power to endure any other Con-<lb />verſation. His Head is
  haunted, like a Houſe,<lb />with evil Spirits and Apparitions, that
  terrify<lb />and fright him out of himſelf, till he ſtands<lb />empty
  and forſaken. His Sleeps and his Wa-<lb />kings are ſo much the ſame,
  that he knows not<lb />how to diſtinguiſh them, and many
  times<lb />when he dreams, he believes he is broad awake<lb />and ſees
  Viſions. The Fumes and Vapours<lb />that riſe from his Spleen and
  Hypocondries<lb />have ſo ſmutched and ſullied his Brain (like
  a<lb />Room that ſmoaks) that his Underſtanding is<lb />blear-ey'd,
  and has no right Perception of any<lb />Thing. His Soul lives in his
  Body, like a<lb />Mole in the Earth, that labours in the
  Dark,<lb />and caſts up Doubts and Scruples of his own</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Imagination, to make that rugged and uneaſy,<lb />that was plain
  and open before. His Brain is<lb />ſo cracked, that he fancies himſelf
  to be Glaſs,<lb />and is afraid that every Thing he comes
  near<lb />ſhould break him in Pieces. Whatſoever makes<lb />an
  Impreſſion in his Imagination works it ſelf<lb />in like a Screw, and
  the more he turns and<lb />winds it, the deeper it ſticks, till it is
  never to<lb />be got out again. The Temper of his Brain<lb />being
  earthy, cold, and dry, is apt to breed<lb />Worms, that ſink ſo deep
  into it, no Medicine<lb />in Art or Nature is able to reach them.
  He<lb />leads his Life, as one leads a Dog in a Slip<lb />that will
  not follow, but is dragged along until<lb />he is almoſt hanged, as he
  has it often under<lb />Conſideration to treat himſelf in
  convenient<lb />Time and Place, if he can but catch
  himſelf<lb />alone. After a long and mortal Feud between<lb />his
  inward and his outward Man, they at<lb />length agree to meet without
  Seconds, and decide the<lb />Quarrel, in which the one drops, and
  the<lb />other ſinks out fo the Way, and makes his<lb />Eſcape into
  ſome foreign World, from whence<lb />is it never after heard of. He
  converſes with<lb />nothing ſo much as his own Imagination,<lb />which
  being apt to miſrepreſent Things to him,</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>makes him believe, that it is ſomething elſe<lb />than it is, and
  that he holds Intelligence with<lb />Spirits, that reveal whatſoever
  he fancies to<lb />him, as the antient rude People, that firſt
  heard<lb />their own Voices repeated by Echoes in the<lb />Woods,
  concluded it muſt proceed from ſome<lb />invisible Inhabitants of
  thoſe ſolitary Places,<lb />which they after believed to be Gods,
  and<lb />called them <hi rendition="simple:italic">Sylvans,
  Fauns,</hi> and <hi rendition="simple:italic">Dryads.</hi>
  He<lb />makes the Infirmity of his Temper paſs for<lb />Revelations,
  as <hi rendition="simple:italic">Mahomet</hi> did by his
  falling<lb />Sickneſs, and inſpires himſelf with the Wind<lb />of his
  own Hypocondries. He laments,
  like<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Heraclitus</hi> the Maudlin
  Philoſopher, at other<lb />Men's Mirth, and take Pleaſures in
  nothing<lb />but his own un-ſober Sadneſs. His Mind is<lb />full of
  Thoughts, but they are all empty, like<lb />a Neſt of Boxes. He ſleeps
  little, but dreams<lb />much, and ſoundeſt when he is waking.
  He<lb />ſees Viſions further off than a ſecond-ſighted<lb />Man in
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Scotland,</hi> and dreams upon a
  hard<lb />Point with admirable Judgement. He is juſt<lb />ſo much
  worſe than a Madman, as he is below<lb />him in Degree of Frenzy; for
  among Madmen<lb />the moſt mad govern all the reſt, and receive<lb />a
  natural Obedience from their Inferiors.</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
