<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />CORRUPT JUDGE</head>
  <p>P<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi><hi rendition="simple:smallcaps">asses</hi>
  Judgement as a Gameſter does<lb />falſe Dice. The firſt Thing he takes
  is<lb />his Oath and his Comiſſion, and afterwards<lb />the ſtrongeſt
  Side and Bribes. He gives Judg-<lb />ment, as the Council at the Bar
  are ſaid to give<lb />Advice, when they are paid for it. He
  wraps<lb />himſelf warm in Furs, that the cold Air may<lb />not ſtrike
  his Conſcience inward. He is never<lb />an upright Judge, but when he
  is weary of<lb />ſitting, and ſtands for his Eaſe. Al the Uſe<lb />he
  make of his Oath is to oppoſe it againſt<lb />his Prince, for whoſe
  Service he firſt took it,<lb />and to bind him with that, which he
  firſt pre-<lb />tended to bind himſelf with; as if the King
  by<lb />imparting a little of his Power to him gave<lb />hi to Title
  to all the reſt, like thoſe who hold-<lb />ing a little Land in
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Capite</hi> render all the
  reſt<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>liable to the ſame Tenure. As for that which<lb />concerns the
  People, he takes his Liberty to do<lb />what he pleaſes ; this he
  maintains with Cant-<lb />ing, of which himſelf being the only
  Judge,<lb />he can give it what arbitrary Interpretation
  he<lb />pleaſes ; yet is a great Enemy to arbitrary<lb />Power,
  becauſe he would have no Body uſe it<lb />but himſelf. If he have Hope
  of Preferment<lb />he makes all the Law run on the King's Side
  ;<lb />if not, it always takes part againſt him ; for as<lb />he was
  bred to make any Thing right or wrong<lb />between Man and Man, ſo he
  can do between<lb />the King and his Subjects. He calls
  himſelf<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Capitalis, &amp;c.</hi>
  which Word he never uſes but<lb />to Crimes of the higeſt Nature. He
  uſurps<lb />unſufferable Tyranny over Words ; for when<lb />he has
  enſlaved and debaſed them from their<lb />original Senſe, he makes
  them ſerves againſt<lb />themselves to ſupport him, and their
  own<lb />Abuſe. He is as ſtiff to Delinquents, and<lb />makes as harſh
  a Noiſe as a new Cart-wheel,<lb />until he is greaſed, and then he
  turns about as<lb />eaſily. He called all necceſſary and
  unavoidable<lb />Proceedings of State, without the
  punctual<lb />Formality of Law, arbitrary and illegal, but<lb />never
  conſiders, that his own Interpretation<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>of Law are more arbitrary, and, when he<lb />pleaſes, illegal. He
  cannot be denied to be a<lb />very impartial Judge ; for right or
  wrong<lb />are all one to him. He takes Bribes, as pious<lb />Men give
  Alms, with ſo much Caution, that<lb />his right Hand never knows what
  his left re-<lb />ceives./</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
