<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A /</head>
  <p>WOOER</p>
  <p>S<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>TANDS Candidate for
  Cuckold, and if<lb />he miſs of it, it is none of his Fault;
  for<lb />his Merit is ſuſſiciently known. He is com<lb />monly no
  Lover, but able to paſs for a moſt<lb />deſperate one, where he finds
  it is like to prove<lb />of conſiderable Advantage to him; and
  there-<lb />fore has Paſſions lying by him of all Sizes
  pro-<lb />portionable to all Women’s Fortunes, and can<lb />be
  indifferent, melancholy, or ſtark-mad, ac-<lb />cording as their
  Eſtates give him Occaſion; and<lb />when he finds it is to no Purpoſe,
  can preſently<lb />come to himſelf again, and try another. He 
  proſecutes his Suit againſt his Miſtreſs as Clients<lb />do a Suit in
  Law, and does nothing without<lb />the Advice of his learned Council,
  omits no<lb />Advantage for want of ſoliciting, and, when<lb />He gets
  her Conſent, overthrows her. He en-<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>deavors to match his Eſtate, rather than him-<lb />ſelſ, to the
  beſt Advantage, and is his Miſ-<lb />treſs’s Fortune and his do but
  come to an<lb />Agreement, their Perſons are eaſily ſatisſied,
  the<lb />Match is ſoon made up, and a Croſs Marriage<lb />between all
  four is prefeſtly concluded. He is<lb />not much concerned in his
  Lady’s Virtues, for if<lb />the Opinion of the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Stoics</hi> be true,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">that the
  vir-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">tuous are always
  rich</hi>, there is no doubt, but ſhe<lb />that is rich muſt be
  virtuous. He never goes<lb />without a Liſt in his Pocket of all the
  Widows<lb />and Virgins about the Town, with Particulars<lb />of their
  Jointures, Portions, and Inheritances,<lb />that if one miſs he may
  not be without a Re-<lb />ſerve; for he eſteems
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Cupid</hi> very improvident,<lb />if he
  has not more than two Strings to his<lb />Bow. When he wants a better
  Introduction,<lb />he begins his Addreſſes to the
  Chamber-maid,<lb />like one that ſues the Tenant to eject the
  Land-<lb />lord, and according as he thrives there makes<lb />his
  Approaches to the Miſtreſs. He can tell<lb />readily what the
  Difference is between Join-<lb />Ture with Tution of Infant, Land
  and<lb />Money of any Value, and what the Odds is<lb />to a Penny
  between them all, either to take or<lb />leave. He does not ſo much go
  a wooing as<lb />put in his Claim, as if all Men of Fortune<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>had a fair Title to all Women of the ſame<lb />Quality, and
  therefore are ſaid to demand them<lb />in Marriage. But if he be a
  Wooer of For-<lb />tune, that deſigns to raiſe himſelſ by it,
  he<lb />makes wooing his Vocation, deals with all<lb />Matchmakers,
  that are his Setters, is very<lb />painful in his Calling, and, if he
  Buſineſs ſucceed,<lb />ſteals her away and commits Matri-<lb />mony
  with a ſelonious Intent. He has a great<lb />deſire to beget Money on
  the Body of a Wo-<lb />man, and as for other Iſſue is very
  indifferent,<lb />and cares not how old ſhe be, ſo ſhe be not
  paſt<lb />Money-bearing.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
