<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>An<lb />Impudent Man</head>
  <p><hi rendition="simple:superscript">I</hi>s one, whoſe want of Money
  and want of<lb />Wit have engaged him beyond his Abilities.<lb />The
  little Knowledge he has of himſelf being<lb />ſuitable to the little
  he has in his Profeſſion has<lb />Made him believe himſelf fit for it.
  This double<lb />Ignorance has made him ſet a Value upon
  him-<lb />ſelf, as he that wants a great deal appears in a<lb />better
  Condition, than he that wants a little.<lb />This renders him
  confident, and fit for any<lb />Undertaking, and ſometimes (ſuch is
  the con-<lb />current Ignorance of the World) he proſpers<lb />In it,
  but oftner miſcarries, and becomes ri-<lb />diculous; yet this
  Advantage he has, that as<lb />nothing can make him ſee his Error, ſo
  he is<lb />fortified with his Ignorance, as barren and<lb />rocky
  Places are by their Situation, and he will<lb />rather believe that
  all Men want Judgment,<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>than himſelf. For as no Man is pleaſed, that<lb />has an ill
  Opinion of himſelſ, Nature, that<lb />finds out Remedies herſelf, and
  his own Eaſe<lb />render him indefenſible of his
  Defects¬—From<lb />hence he grows impudent; for as Men judge<lb />by
  Compariſon, he knows as little what it is<lb />To be defective, as
  what it is to be excellent.<lb />Nothing renders Men modeſt, but a
  juſt Know-<lb />ledge how to compare themſelves with others;<lb />and
  where that is wanting, Impudence supplies<lb />the Place of it: for
  there is no Vacuum in the<lb />Minds of Men, and commonly, like
  other<lb />Things in Nature, they ſwell more with Rare-<lb />faction
  than Condenſation. The more Men<lb />know of the World, the worſe
  Opinion they<lb />have of it; and the more they underſtand
  of<lb />Truth, they are better acquainted with the<lb />Difficulties
  of it, and conſsequently are the leſs<lb />confident in their
  Aſſertions, eſpecially in mat-<lb />ters of Probability, which
  commonly is ſquint-<lb />ey’d, and looks nine Ways at once. It is
  the<lb />Office of a juſt Judge to hear both Parties, and<lb />he that
  conſiders but the one Side of Things<lb />can never make a juſt
  Judgment, though he<lb />may by Chance a true one. Impudence is
  the<lb />Baſtard of Ignorance, not only unlawfully,<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>but inceſtouſsly begotten by a Man upon his<lb />own Underſtanding,
  and laid by himſelſ at<lb />his own Door, a Monſter of unnatural
  Pro-<lb />duction; for Shame is as much the Propriety<lb />of human
  Nature (though overſeen by the<lb />Philoſsophers) and perhaps more
  than Reaſon,<lb />Laughing, or looking aſquint, by which
  they<lb />diſtinguish Man from Beaſts; and the leſs<lb />Men have of
  it, the nearer they approach to<lb />the Nature of Brutes. Modeſty is
  but a noble<lb />Jealouſy of Honour, and Impudence the
  Proſ-<lb />titution of it; for he, whoſe Face is proof<lb />againſt
  Infamy, muſt be as little ſenſible of<lb />Glory. His Forehead, like a
  voluntary Cuck-<lb />old’s is by his Horns made Proof againſt
  a<lb />Bluſh. Nature made Man barefaced, and civil<lb />Cuſtom has
  preſerved him ſo; but he that’s im-<lb />pudent does wear a Vizard
  more ugly and de-<lb />formed than Highway Thieves diſguiſe
  them-<lb />ſelves with. Shame is the tender moral Con-<lb />ſcience of
  good Men. When there is a Crack<lb />In the Skull, Nature herſelf with
  a tough horny<lb />Callus repairs the Breach; ſo a flaw’d Intellect is
  with a brawny Callus Face ſupplied. The<lb />Face is the Dial of the
  Mind; and where they<lb />Do not go together, ‘tis a Sign, that one
  or<lb />Both are out of Order. He that is impudent<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>is like a Merchant, that trades upon his Cre-<lb />dit without a
  Stock, and if his Debts were<lb />known, would break immediately. The
  Inſide<lb />of his Head is like the Outſide; and his Peruke<lb />as
  naturally of his own Growth, as his Wit.<lb />He paſſes in the World
  like a Piece of Counter-<lb />feit Coin, looks well enough until he is
  rubbed<lb />and worn with Uſe, and then his Copper Com-<lb />plexion
  begins to appear, and nobody will take<lb />Him, but by Owl-light.</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
