<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>An<lb />Imitator</head>
  <p><hi rendition="simple:superscript">I</hi>s a counterfeit Stone, and
  the larger and<lb />fairer he appears the more apt he is to
  be<lb />diſcovered, whilſt ſmall ones, that pretend to no great Value,
  paſs unſuſpected. He is made<lb />like a Man in Arras-Hangings, after
  ſome great<lb />Maſter’s Deſign, though far ſhort of the
  Ori<lb />ginal. He is like a Spectrum or walking<lb />Spirit that
  aſſumes the Shape of ſome particular<lb />Peſson, and appears in the
  Likeneſs of ſome-<lb />thing that he is not, becauſe he has no
  Shape<lb />of his own to put on. He has a Kind of<lb />Monkey and
  Baboon Wit, that takes after ſome<lb />Man’s Way, whom he endeavors to
  imitate,<lb />but does it worſse than thoſe Things that are
  na-<lb />turally his own; for he does not learn but<lb />take his
  Pattern out, as a Girl does her Sam-<lb />pler. His whole Life is
  nothing but a Kind of<lb />Education, and he is always learning to
  be<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>ſomething that he is not, nor ever will be: For<lb />Nature is
  free, and will not be forced out of<lb />her Way, nor compelled to do
  any Thing<lb />againſt her own Will and Inclination. He is<lb />but a
  Retainer to Wit, and a Follower of his<lb />Maſter, whoſe Badge he
  wears every where,<lb />and therefore his Way is called
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">ſervile Imitation.</hi><lb />His Fancy
  is like the innocent Lady’s; who by<lb />looking on the Picture of a
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Moor</hi> that hung<lb />in her Chamber
  conceived a Child of the ſame<lb />Complexion; for all his Conceptions
  are pro-<lb />duced by the Pictures of other Men’s
  Imagi-<lb />nations, and by their Features betray whoſe<lb />Baſtards
  they are. His Muſe is not inſpired<lb />but infected with another
  Man’s Fancy; and<lb />he catches his Wit, like the Itch, of
  ſomebody<lb />elſe that had it before, and when he writes he<lb />does
  but ſcratch himſelf. His Head is, like<lb />his Hat, faſhioned upon a
  Block, and wrought<lb />in a Shape of another Man’s Invention.
  He<lb />melts down his Wit, and caſts it in a Mold:<lb />and as metals
  melted and caſt are not ſo firm<lb />and ſolid, as thoſe that are
  wrought with the<lb />Hammer; ſo thoſe Compoſitions, that
  are<lb />founded and run in other Men’s Molds, are<lb />always more
  brittle and looſe than thoſe, that<lb />are forged in a Man’s own
  Brain. He binds<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>himſelf Prentice to a Trade, which he has no<lb />Stock to ſet up
  with, if he ſhould ſerve out his<lb />Time, and live to be made free.
  He runs a<lb />whoring after another Man’s Inventions (for he<lb />has
  none of his own to tempt him to an incon-<lb />tinent Thought) and
  begets a Kind of Mun-<lb />grel Breed, that never comes to
  good.<lb />---</p>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
