<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />QUAKER</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>S a Scoundrel Saint, of
  an Order without<lb />Founder, Vow, or Rule ; for he will
  not<lb />ſwear, nor be tyed to any Thing, but his own<lb />Humour. He
  is the Link-Boy of the Sectaries,<lb />and talks much of his Light,
  but puts it under<lb />a Buſhel, for nobody can ſee it but himſelf.
  His<lb />Religion is but the cold Fit of an Ague, and his<lb />Zeal of
  a contrary Temper to that of all others,<lb />yet produces the ſame
  Effects ; as cold Iron
  in<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Greenland</hi>, they ſay, burns
  as well as hot ;<lb />which makes him delight, like a
  Salamander,<lb />to live in the Fire of Perſecution. He works<lb />out
  his Salvation, not with <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fear</hi>, but
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Confidence</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">and
  Trembling</hi>. His Profeſſion is but a Kind<lb />of Winter-Religion ;
  and the Original of it as<lb />uncertain as the hatching of Woodcocks,
  for<lb />no Man can tell from whence it came. He<lb />Vapours much of
  the Light within him, but<lb />no ſuch Thing appears, unleſs he means
  as he<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>is light-headed. He believes he takes up the<lb />Croſs in being
  croſs to all Mankind. He de_<lb />lights in Perſecution, as ſome old
  extravagant<lb />Fornicators find a Lechery in being whipt ;<lb />and
  has no Ambition but to go to Heaven in<lb />what he calls a fiery
  Chariot, that is, a Wood-<lb />monger’s Faggot Cart. You may perceive
  he<lb />has a Crack in his Skull by the flat Twang of<lb />his Noſe,
  and the great Care he takes to keep<lb />his Hat on, leſt his ſickly
  Brains, if he have<lb />any, ſhould take Cold at it. He believes
  his<lb />Doctrine to be heavenly, becauſe it agrees per-<lb />fectly
  with the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Motus Trepidationis</hi>. All
  his<lb />Hopes are in the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Turks</hi>
  overrunning of Chriſ-<lb />tendom, becauſe he has heard they count
  Fools<lb />and Madmen Saints, and doubts not to paſs<lb />muſter with
  them for great Abilities that Way.<lb />This makes him believe he can
  convert the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Turk</hi>,<lb />tho’ he
  could do no good on the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Pope</hi>, or
  the<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Preſbyterian</hi>. Nothing
  comes ſo near his quak-<lb />ing Liturgy, as the Papiſtical
  Poſſeſſions of the<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Devil</hi>, with
  which it conforms in Diſcipline<lb />exact. His Church, or rather
  Chapel, is built<lb />upon a flat Sand, without ſuperior or
  inferior<lb />in it, and not upon a Rock, which is never<lb />found
  without great Inequalities. Next De_<lb />moniacs he moſt reſembles
  the Reprobate, who<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>are ſaid to be condemned to Weeping and<lb />Gnaſhing of Teeth.
  There was a Botcher of<lb />their Church, that renounced his Trade
  and<lb />turned Preacher, becauſe he held it ſuperſtiti-<lb />ous to
  ſit <hi rendition="simple:italic">croſs-legged</hi>. His Devotion is
  but a<lb />Kind of ſpiritual Palſy, that proceeds from
  a<lb />Diſtemper in the Brain, where the Nerves are<lb />rooted. They
  abhor the Church of
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">England</hi>,<lb />but conform exactly
  with thoſe primitive Fa-<lb />thers of their Church, that heretofore
  gave An-<lb />ſwers at the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Devil</hi>’s
  Oracles, in which they ob-<lb />ſerved the very ſame Ceremony of
  quaking and<lb />and gaping now practiſed by our modern
  En_<lb />thuſiaſts at their Exorciſms, rather than Ex-<lb />erciſes of
  Devotion. He ſucks in the Air like<lb />a Pair of Bellows, and blows
  his inward Light<lb />with it, till he dung Fire, as Cattle do in
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Lin</hi>-<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">colnſhire</hi>.
  The general Ignorance of their<lb />whole Party make it appear, that
  whatſoever<lb />their Zeal may be, it is not
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">according to
  Know</hi>-<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">ledge</hi>.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
