<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />RIBALD</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>S the Devil’s Hypocrite,
  the endeavours to<lb />make himſelf appear worſe than he is.
  His<lb />evil Words and bad Manners ſtrive which<lb />ſhall moſt
  corrupt one another, and it is hard<lb />to ſay which has the
  Advantage. He vents<lb />his Lechery at the Mouth, as ſome Fiſhes
  are<lb />ſaid to engender. He is an unclean Beaſt that<lb />chews the
  Cud ; for after he has ſatisfied his<lb />Lust, he brings it up again
  into his Mouth<lb />to a ſecond Enjoyment, and plays an
  After-<lb />game of Letchery with his Tongue much worſe<lb />than that
  which the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Cunnilingi</hi> uſed among
  the<lb />old <hi rendition="simple:italic">Romans.</hi> He ſtrips
  Nature ſtark-naked, and<lb />clothes her in the moſt fantaſtic and
  ridiculous<lb />Faſhion a wild Imagination can invent. He<lb />is
  worſe and more naſty than a Dog ; for<lb />in his broad Deſcriptions
  of others obſcene<lb />Actions he does but lick up the Vomit of
  ano-<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>ther Man’s Surfeits. He tells Tales out of a<lb />vaulting School.
  A leud baudy Tale does<lb />more Hurt, and gives a worſe Example
  than<lb />the Thing of which it was told ; for the Act<lb />extends
  but to a few, and if it be concealed<lb />goes no further ; but the
  Report of it is un-<lb />limited, and may be conveyed to all
  People,<lb />and all Times to come. He expoſes that with<lb />his
  Tongue, which Nature gave Women Mo-<lb />deſty, and brute Beaſts Tails
  to cover. He<lb />miſtakes Ribaldry for Wit, though nothing
  is<lb />more unlike, and believes himſelf to be the<lb />finer Man the
  filthier he talks ; as if he were<lb />above Civility, as
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fanatics</hi> are above
  Ordinan-<lb />ces, and held nothing more ſhameful than to
  be<lb />aſhamed of any Thing. He talks nothing
  but<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Aretine</hi>’s Pictures, as
  plain as the <hi rendition="simple:italic">Scotch</hi> Dia-<lb />lect,
  which is eſteemed to be the moſt copious<lb />and elegant of the Kind.
  He improves and<lb />huſbands his Sins to the beſt Advantage,<lb />and
  makes one Vice find Employment for<lb />another ; for what he acts
  looſely in private,<lb />he talks as looſely of in public, and finds
  as<lb />much Pleaſure in the one as the other. He<lb />endeavours to
  make himſelf Satisfaction for<lb />the Pangs his Claps and Botches put
  him to with<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>vapouring and bragging how he came by<lb />them. He endeavours to
  purchaſe himſelf a<lb />Reputation by pretending to that which
  the<lb />beſt Men abominate, and the worſt value not,<lb />like one
  that clips and waſhes falſe Coin, and<lb />ventures his Neck for that
  which will yield<lb />him nothing.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
