<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
      <p></p>
          </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
      <p>Produced by pandoc.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]</p>
<div type="level1">
  <head>PREFACE.</head>
  <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">T<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>HE
  writing of Characters was a Kind of
  Wit</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">much in Faſhion in the
  Beginning of the laſt</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Century,
  The two principal Authors in this
  Way</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">were Sir</hi> Thomas
  Overbury, <hi rendition="simple:italic">and Dr.</hi> John<lb />Earle
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Tutor to Prince</hi> Charles
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">in</hi> 1643,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">and
  after</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">the Reſtoration Dean
  of</hi> Weſtminſter, <hi rendition="simple:italic">and
  ſuc-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">ceſſively Biſhop of</hi>
  Worceſter <hi rendition="simple:italic">and</hi> Saliſbury.
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">How</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">agreeable
  theſe Sorts of Eſſays were to the
  public</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Taſte may be judged
  from Sir</hi> Thomas's <hi rendition="simple:italic">little
  Book</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">having fourteen Editions
  before</hi> 1632, <hi rendition="simple:italic">and
  the</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Biſhop's ſix between</hi>
  1628 <hi rendition="simple:italic">and</hi> 1633.
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Whether</hi><lb />Butler
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">has equalled or excelled them, and
  what</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Place he is to hold in
  this Claſs of Writers muſt</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">be
  left to the Deciſion of the Public, as the
  Inte-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">reſt and Prejudice of a
  Publiſher may render me</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">a
  ſuſpected or an incompetent Judge. The
  Reader</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">will have an
  Opportunity of determining for
  him</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">ſelf, as they have all
  attempted to draw the
  ſame</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Pictures.</hi><lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">As in ſuch a Variety of Characters
  there muſt</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">be ſome drawn from
  Originals in general the
  ſame,</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">and only differenced by
  particular Circumſtances,</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">the
  ſame Obſervations are ſometimes
  repeated.</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Whether the Author
  in this Caſe requires any
  Apo-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">logy muſt be left to his
  Judges the Critics ; it
  is</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">enough for me that I can
  ſay I have done him</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Justice in
  publiſhing them.</hi></p>
  <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">As moſt of theſe Characters are dated
  when they</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">were compoſed, I can
  inform the curious, that
  they</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">were chiefly drawn up
  from</hi> 1667 <hi rendition="simple:italic">to</hi> 1669,
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">at</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">which
  time, as has been before obſerved,</hi>
  Butler<lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">reſided in</hi> Wales
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">under the Protection of
  Lord</hi><lb />Carbery.</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
</div>
<div type="level1">
  <head>A<lb />HUFFING COURTIER</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>s a Cypher, that has no
  Value himſelf, but<lb />from the Place he ſtands in. All his
  Hap-<lb />pineſs conſiſts in the Opinion he believes others<lb />have
  of it. This is his Faith, but as it is he-<lb />retical and erroneous,
  though he ſuffer much<lb />Tribulation for it, he continues obſtinate,
  and<lb />not to be convinced. He flutters up and down<lb />like a
  Butterfly in a Garden ; and while he is<lb />pruning of his Peruque
  takes Occaſion to con-<lb />template his Legs, and the Symmetry of
  his<lb />Britches. He is part of the Furniture of the<lb />Rooms, and
  ſerves for a walking Picture, a<lb />moving Piece of Arras. His
  Buſineſs is only<lb />to be ſeen, and he performs it with
  admirable<lb />Industry, placing himself always in the
  beſt<lb />Light, looking wonderfully Politic, and cau-<lb />tious whom
  he mixes withal. His Occupation<lb />is to ſhow his Cloaths, and if
  they could but<lb />walk themselves, they would ſave him the </p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>Labour, and do his Work as well as himſelf.<lb />His Immunity from
  Varlets is his Freehold,<lb />and he were a loſt Man without it.
  His<lb />Cloaths are but his Taylor's Livery, which he<lb />gives him,
  for ’tis ten to one he never pays for<lb />them. He is very careful to
  diſcover the Lining<lb />of his Coat, that you may not ſuſpect
  any<lb />Want of Integrity of Flaw in him from the<lb />Skin outwards.
  His Taylor is his Creator,<lb />and makes him of nothing ; and though
  he<lb />lives by Faith in him, he is perpetually com_<lb />mitting
  Iniquities againſt him. His Soul dwells<lb />in the Outſide of him,
  like that of a hollow<lb />Tree ; and if you do but pill the Bark off
  him<lb />he deceaſes immediately. His Carriage of<lb />himſelf is the
  wearing of his Cloaths, and,<lb />like the Cinamon Tree, his Bark is
  better than<lb />his Body. His looking big is rather a
  Tumor,<lb />than Greatneſs. He is an Idol, that has juſt<lb />ſo much
  Value, as other Men give him that<lb />believe in him, but none of his
  own. He<lb />makes him Ignorance paſs for Reſerve, and, like<lb />a
  Hunting-nag, leaps over what he cannot get<lb />through. He has juſt
  ſo much of Politics, as<lb />Hoſtlers in the Univerſity have
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Latin</hi>. He is<lb />as humble as a
  Jeſuit to his Superior ; but re-<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>pays himſelf again in Inſolence over thoſe, that<lb />are below
  him ; and with a generous Scorn<lb />deſpiſes thoſe, that can neither
  do him good,<lb />nor hurt. He adores thoſe, that may do
  him<lb />good, though he knows they never will ; and<lb />deſpiſes
  thoſe, that would not hurt him, if<lb />they could. The Court is his
  Church, and he<lb />believes as that believes, and cries up and
  down<lb />every Thing, as he finds it paſs there. It is a<lb />great
  Comfort to him to think, that ſome who<lb />do not know him may
  perhaps take him for a<lb />Lord ; and while that Thought laſts he
  looks<lb />bigger than uſual, and forgets his Acquain-<lb />tance ;
  and that's the Reaſon why he will ſome-<lb />times know you, and
  ſometimes not. Nothing<lb />but want of Money or Credit puts him
  in<lb />mind that he is mortal ; but then he truſts<lb />Providence
  that ſomebody will truſt him ; and<lb />in Expectation of that hopes
  for a better Life,<lb />and that his Debts will never riſe up in
  Judg-<lb />ment against him. To get in debt is to labour<lb />in his
  Vocation ; but to pay is to forfeit his<lb />Protection ; for what’s
  that worth to one that<lb />owes Nothing ? His Employment being only
  to<lb />wear his Cloaths, the whole Account of his<lb />Life and
  Actions is recorded in Shopkeepers<lb />Books, that are his faithful
  Hiſtoriographers to<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>their own Poſterity ; and he believes he loſes<lb />ſo much
  Reputation, as he pays off his Debts ;<lb />and that no Man wears his
  Cloaths in Faſhion,<lb />that pays for them, for noting is further
  from<lb />the Mode. He believes that he that runs in<lb />Debt is
  beforehand with thoſe that truſt him,<lb />and only thoſe, that pay,
  are behind. His<lb />Brains are turned giddy, like one that
  walks<lb />on the Top of a Houſe ; and that’s the Reaſon<lb />it is ſo
  troubleſome to him to look downwards.<lb />He is a Kind of Spectrum,
  and his Cloaths are<lb />the Shape he takes to appear and walk in ;
  and<lb />when he puts them off he vaniſhes. He runs<lb />as buſily out
  of one Room into another, as a<lb />great Practiſer does in
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Weſtminſter</hi>-Hall from<lb />one
  Court to another. When he accoſts a<lb />Lady he puts both Ends of his
  Microcoſm in<lb />Motion, by making Legs at one End, and<lb />combing
  his Peruque at the other. His Gar-<lb />niture is the Sauce to his
  Cloaths, and he walks<lb />in his Portcannons like one, that ſtalks in
  long<lb />Graſs. Every Motion of him crys
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Vanity
  of</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Vanities, all is
  Vanity,</hi> quoth the Preacher. He<lb />rides himself like a
  well-managed Horſe, reins<lb />in his Neck, and walks
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Terra Terra</hi>. He<lb />carries his
  elbows backward, as if he were<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>pinioned like a truſt-up Fowl, and moves as<lb />ſtiff as if he was
  upon the Spit. His Legs are<lb />ſtuck in his great voluminous
  Britches, like<lb />the Whiſtles in a Bagpipe, thoſe
  abundant<lb />Britches, in which his nether Parts are
  not<lb />cloathed, but packt up. His Hat has been long<lb />in a
  Conſumption of the Faſhion, and is now<lb />almoſt worn to Nothing ;
  if it do not recover<lb />quickly it will grown too little for a Head
  of<lb />Garlick. He wears Garniture on the Toes of<lb />his Shoes to
  juſtify his Prentenſions to the Gout,<lb />or ſuch other Malady, that
  for the Time being<lb />is moſt in Fashion or Requeſt. When
  he<lb />ſalutes a Friend he pulls off his Hat, as Wo-<lb />men do
  their Vizard-Maſques. His Ribbons<lb />are of the true Complexion of
  his Mind, a<lb />Kind of painted Cloud or gawdy Rainbow,<lb />that has
  no Colour of it ſelf, but what is bor-<lb />rows from Reflection. He
  is as tender of his<lb />Cloaths, as a Coward is of his Fleſh, and
  as<lb />loth to have them diſordered. His Bravery<lb />is all his
  Happineſs ; and like <hi rendition="simple:italic">Atlas</hi> he
  carries<lb />his Heaven on his Back. He is like the
  golden<lb />Fleece, a fine Outſide on a Sheep’s Back. He<lb />is a
  Monſter or an <hi rendition="simple:italic">Indian</hi> Creature, that
  is<lb />good for nothing in the World but to be ſeen.<lb />He puts
  himſelf up into a Sedan, like a Fiddle<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>in a Caſe, and is taken out again for the La-<lb />dies to play
  upon, who when they have done<lb />with him, let down his
  treble-String, till they<lb />are in the Humour again. His Cook and
  Va-<lb />let de Chambre conſpire to dreſs Dinner and<lb />him ſo
  punctually together, that the one may<lb />not be ready before the
  other. As Peacocks and<lb />Oſtridges have the gaudieſt and fineſt
  Feathers,<lb />yet cannot fly ; ſo all his Bravery is to
  flutter<lb />only. The Beggars call him
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">my Lord,</hi> and he<lb />takes them at
  their Words, and pays them for<lb />it. If you praiſe him, he is ſo
  true and faith-<lb />ful to the Mode, that he never fails to
  make<lb />you a Preſent of himſelf, and will not be re-<lb />fuſed,
  tho’ you know not what to do with him<lb />when you have
  him.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">double rule</hi>]</p>
</div>
<div type="level1">
  <head>AN<lb />ANTIQUARY</head>
  <p>I<hi rendition="simple:superscript">2</hi>s one that has his Being
  in this Age, but<lb />his Life and Converſation is in the Days
  of<lb />old. He deſpiſes the preſent Age as an Inno-<lb />vation, and
  ſlights the future ; but has a great<lb />Value for that, which is
  paſt and gone, like<lb />the Madman, that fell in Love with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Cleopatra</hi>.<lb />He is an old
  frippery-Philoſopher, that has<lb />ſo ſtrange a natural Affection to
  worm-eaten<lb />Speculation, that it is apparent he has a Worm<lb />in
  his Skull. He honours his Forefathers and<lb />Fore-mothers, but
  condemns his Parents as<lb />too modern, and no better than Upſtarts.
  He<lb />neglects himſelf, becauſe he was born in his<lb />own Time,
  and ſo far off Antiquity, which<lb />he ſo much admires ; and repines,
  like a<lb />younger Brother, becauſe he came ſo late into<lb />the
  World. He ſpends the one half of his<lb />Time in collecting old
  inſignificant Trifles,<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>and the other in ſhewing them, which he takes<lb />ſingular Delight
  in ; becauſe the oftener he does<lb />it, the further they are from
  being new to him.<lb />All his Curiouſities take place of one
  another<lb />according to their Seniority, and he values<lb />them not
  by their Abilities, but their Standing.<lb />He has a great Veneration
  for Words that are<lb />ſtricken in Years, and are grown ſo aged,
  that<lb />they have out-lived their Employments---Theſe<lb />he uſes
  with a Reſpect agreeable to their An-<lb />tiquity, and the good
  Services they have done.<lb />He throws away his Time in enquiring
  after<lb />that which is paſt and gone ſo many Ages ſince,<lb />like
  one that ſhoots away an Arrow, to find<lb />out another that was loſt
  before. He fetches<lb />things out of Duſt and Ruins, like the
  Fable<lb />of the chymical Plant raiſed out of its own<lb />Aſhes. He
  values one old Invention, that is<lb />loſt and never to be recovered,
  before all the<lb />new ones in the World, tho’ never ſo
  uſeful.<lb />The whole Buſineſs of his Life is the ſame with<lb />his,
  that ſhows the Tombs at
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Westminster</hi>, only<lb />the one does
  it for his Pleaſure, and the other<lb />for Money. As every Man has
  but one Fa-<lb />ther, but two Grand-Fathers and a World<lb />of
  Anceſtors ; ſo he has a proportional Value<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>for Things that are antient, and the further off<lb />the
  greater.</p>
  <p>He is a great Time-ſerver, but it is of Time<lb />out of Mind, to
  which he conforms exactly,<lb />but is wholly retied from the preſent.
  His<lb />Days were ſpent and gone long before he came<lb />into the
  World, and ſince his only Buſineſs is<lb />to collect what he can out
  of the Ruins of<lb />them. He has ſo ſtrong a natural Affection
  to<lb />any Thing that is old, that he may truly
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">ſay
  to</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">Duſt and Worms you are my
  Father, and to Rot-</hi><lb /><hi rendition="simple:italic">tenneſs
  thou are my Mother</hi>. He has no Provi-<lb />dence nor Fore-ſight ;
  for all his Contempla-<lb />tions look backward upon the Days of
  old,<lb />and his Brains are turned with them, as if he<lb />walked
  backwards. He had rather interpret<lb />one obſcure Word in any old
  ſenſeleſs Diſ-<lb />courſe, than be the Author of the moſt
  ingenious<lb />new one ; and with
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Scaliger</hi> would ſell the<lb />Empire
  of <hi rendition="simple:italic">Germany</hi>[^1] (if it were in his
  Power)<lb />for an old Song. He devours an old Manuſ-<lb />cript with
  greater Reliſh than Worms and Moths<lb />do, and, though there be
  nothing in it, values<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>it above any Thing printed, which he accounts<lb />but a Novelty.
  When he happens to cure a<lb />ſmall Botch in an old Author, he is as
  proud<lb />of it, as if he had got the Philoſophers Stone,<lb />and
  could cure all the Diſeaſes of Mankind.<lb />He values things
  wrongfully upon their Anti-<lb />quity, forgetting that the moſt
  modern are<lb />really the moſt ancient of all Things in
  the<lb />World, like thoſe that reckon their Pounds<lb />before their
  Shillings and Pence, of which they<lb />are made up. He eſteems no
  Cuſtoms but ſuch<lb />as have outlived themſelves, and are long
  ſince<lb />out of Uſe ; as the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Catholics</hi> allow of no
  Saints,<lb />but ſuch as are dead, and the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Fanatics</hi>, Op-<lb />poſition, of
  none but the Living.<lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two rules</hi>]<lb /><lb />#
  AN<lb /># ALDERMAN<lb /><lb />[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two line
  initial</hi>]HAS taken his Degree in Cheating,
  and<lb />[<hi rendition="simple:italic">two line initial</hi>] the
  higheſt of his Faculty ; or paid for<lb />refuſing his
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">MANDAMUS</hi>. He is a Peer of
  the<lb />City, and a Member of their upper Houſe,<lb />Who, as ſoon as
  he arrives at ſo many thouſand<lb />Pounds, is bound by the Charter to
  ſerve the<lb />Public with ſo much Underſtanding, what<lb />ſhift
  ſoever he make to raiſe it, and wear a<lb />Chain about his Neck like
  a Raindeer, or in<lb />Default to commute, and make Satisfaction
  in<lb />ready Money, the beſt Reaſon of the Place;<lb />for which hi
  has the Name only, like a titular<lb />Prince, and is an
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Alderman extraordinary</hi>. But<lb />if
  his Wife can prevail with him to ſtand, he<lb />becomes one of the
  City-ſupporters, and, like<lb />the Unicorn in the King's Arms, wears
  a Chain<lb />about his Neck very right-worſhipfully. He<lb />wears
  Scarlet, as the Whore of <hi rendition="simple:italic">Babylon</hi>
  does,<lb />not for her honeſty, but the Rank and
  Quality<lb /><lb /></p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>ſhe is of among the Wicked, When he ſits as a Judge in his Court he
  is abſolute, and uſes arbitrary Power ; for he is not bound to un-
  derſtand what he does, nor render an Account why he gives Judgment on
  one Side rather than another ; but his Will is ſufficient to ſtand for
  his Reaſon, to all Intents and Purpoſes. He does no public Buſineſs
  without eating and drinking, and never meets about Matters of Im-
  portance, but the Cramming his Inſide is the moſt weighty Part of the
  Work of the Day. He diſpatches no public Affair until he has
  thoroughly dined upon it, and is fully ſatisfied with Quince-Pye and
  Cuſtard : for Men are wiſer, the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Italians</hi> ſay, after their Bellies
  are full, than when they are faſting, and he is very cautious to omit
  no Occaſion of improving his Parts that Way. He is ſo careful of the
  In- tereſt of his Belly, and manages it ſo induſ- triouſly, that in a
  little Space it grows great and takes Place of all the reſt of his
  Members, and becomes ſo powerful, that they will never be in a
  Condition to rebel againſt it any more. He is cloathed in Scarlet the
  Livery of his Sins, like the rich Glutton, to put him in Mind of what
  Means he came to his Wealth and Pre- ferment by. He makes a Trade of
  his Eat-</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>This is Sarah testing testing testing</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
  <p>ing, and, like a Cock, ſcrapes when he feeds; for the Public pays
  for all and more, which he and his Brethren ſhare among themſelves ;
  for they never make a dry Reckoning. When he comes to be Lord-Mayor he
  does not keep a great Houſe, but a very great Houſe-warming for a
  whole Year ; for though he invites all the
  <hi rendition="simple:italic">Companies</hi> in the City he does not
  treat them, but they club to entertain him, and pay the Reckoning
  beforehand. His Fur-gown makes him look a great deal bigger than he
  is, like the Feathers of an Owl, and when he pulls it off, he looks as
  if he were fallen away, or like a Rabbet, had his Skin pulled off.</p>
  <milestone unit="undefined" type="separator" rendition="line" />
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
